Tokyo MER is a medical organization that reports directly to the governor.
東京行動急診室 是直屬於都知事的醫療單位
They have just one mission.
他們只有一項使命
To make sure there are zero casualties.
不讓任何人喪生
Some lives can't be saved by just waiting.
如果只是在原地等待 也許會錯失拯救生命的機會
They'll never abandon anybody.
他們是絕不會見死不救的
It's the anesthetist's job to protect the patient in the OR.
守護手術室的患者是麻醉醫師的工作
Doctors and nurses aren't the only ones saving lives.
能救人的不是只有醫生和護理師而已
Which is more important, human lives or your boss's orders?
人命和命令，到底哪個更重要啊？
You can't operate here!
怎麼能在這裡動手術？
You're a doctor. Save these people.
是醫生的話，就給我盡全力救人
I'm a useless person. Why did you pick me for MER?
你為什麼挑我這種 派不上用場的人進行動急診室？
The reason you became a doctor. "Because I want to save lives."
你想當醫生的原因是想拯救生命吧？
Doctors like that are actually hard to find.
其實這樣的醫生並不多呢
Doctors who just simply want to save lives.
只是單純想救人的醫生
Will you go out with me with the prospect of marriage?
你願意以結婚為前提跟我交往嗎？
HALF A YEAR LATER
（半年後）
Please.
請你答應我
It's too formal, Kitami.
太死板了，喜多見
Really?
會嗎？
"The prospect of marriage"? It's too much.
太凝重了，“以結婚為前提”什麼的
Let's just keep this as a birthday celebration.
那就這樣慶祝生日就好了嘛
No, when it comes to things like this, someone has to force it through.
不行，這種事就得有人先踏出第一步
Just do the proposal the way I told you to.
總之照著媒婆我說的去做就對了
What do I say?
我該怎麼說啊？
You should probably clean this place up first.
你還是先收拾一下房子吧
I already did.
已經收拾好啦
Besides, you should practice with Governor Akatsuka and not me.
而且你不應該找我 應該跟赤塚知事練習才對
I can't practice with a woman.
跟別的女性練習這種事有點那個
I don't particularly enjoy this either.
我也感覺不舒服
Right.
也對
Sorry for asking so much.
抱歉，老是麻煩你
I was just roped into this by Governor Akatsuka.
反正是赤塚知事找我來的
You're going back to the Ministry soon, right?
你要回厚勞省了吧？
Until then, I plan to keep you on as our spy.
在那之前 我打算讓你繼續當我們的間諜喔
Anyway, have you found a new second doctor to replace Dr. Otowa?
對了，找到新醫師 接替音羽醫師的副手職務了嗎？
Not yet.
還沒
What are you going to do?
那要怎麼辦？
Are you planning to make Dr. Hina your second doctor after her residency?
你該不會要比奈醫師 在研修結束後接任副手吧？
What does she think?
她怎麼想？
I haven't talked to her about it.
我還沒問她
It's just that Dr. Takanawa said that
不過，高輪醫師說
she's sure Dr. Hina will become an excellent cardiac surgeon.
比奈醫師以後 會是一位優秀的心臟外科醫師
Dr. Takanawa. The results of the echocardiogram are good,
高輪醫師，心臟超音波的結果良好
and we found nothing on the X-rays either.
X光檢查也沒有異常
Kurumi.
胡桃
If you keep this up, we can discharge you next week.
再保持下去的話，下週就能出院了喔
That's amazing, Kurumi.
太好了呢，胡桃
You'll be able to carry the Omikoshi this year.
那你今年就能抬神轎囉
What's wrong?
怎麼啦？
She really likes Dr. Hina,
這孩子很喜歡比奈醫師
so she's sad that she'll have to say goodbye.
不捨得離開這裡
You know,
跟你說喔
I'll be really happy once you get well enough to leave the hospital.
我最想看到的是你能健健康康地出院
We can see each other anytime.
我們以後隨時都能再見嘛
He's proposing?!
-求婚？
Chief Kitami is proposing to Dr. Takanawa?
什麼？喜多見主任 要向高輪醫師求婚嗎？
Apparently, Governor Akatsuka is pushing him to do it.
聽說是赤塚知事一直催婚
But they got divorced once, right?
但他們倆離過一次婚了吧？
Do you think Dr. Takanawa wants to?
高輪醫師會答應嗎？
I don't think it bothers her that much.
我覺得她並不抗拒吧
I'm sure she has an idea that he wants to.
喜多見主任的心思 她應該也有所察覺吧
Isn't it fine?
這很好啊
After all, Dr. Takanawa is the one who's held him up
涼香小姐去世後 都是高輪醫師在喜多見主任身邊
ever since Ms. Suzuka passed away.
默默支持著他啊
How do you know so much about them, Ms. Natsumi?
話說回來，夏梅小姐 你怎麼知道得那麼詳細？
Chief Kitami asked me to find out whatever I could
喜多見主任拜託我幫他
about how she feels about him.
探聽高輪醫師的想法
We're not in middle school anymore.
像個中學生似的
Chief Kitami doesn't seem like the type to do well at that sort of thing.
畢竟喜多見主任不擅長這種事嘛
Risk Management Control.
都廳危機管理對策室通報
The special effects system at a theater in Koto City has exploded.
江東區劇場的舞台特效設備發生爆炸
Injuries confirmed.
出現傷患
It's a small-scale medical incident. Requesting Tokyo MER.
判定為小規模緊急醫療事件 請求東京行動急診室出動
Dr. Hina.
比奈醫師
Copy that. On our way.
收到，立即出動
This is Takanawa.
我是高輪
It's Kitami.
我是喜多見
I know. A dispatch, right?
我知道，要出動，對吧？
Dr. Hina already went.
比奈醫師已經過去了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Oh, and happy birthday.
對了，生日快樂
He hasn't changed.
還是老樣子
Eight confirmed injuries. Some appear to be serious.
已確認的傷患有八名 其中有部分重傷患者
Panicked audience members have fallen on the stairs,
有觀眾在慌亂中摔下樓梯
leading to additional injuries. Rescue operations are ongoing.
傷患人數持續增加，救援仍在進行中
This is Komaba. Situation has elevated to mid-scale, risk level increased.
我是駒場 現場升級為中規模緊急醫療事件
Request for assistance has been issued to nearby hospitals.
已向附近的醫院請求醫療協助
MER, copy. We're almost there.
行動急診室收到，即將抵達現場
The lights have been damaged by the explosion.
照明設備因爆炸遭到破壞
Rescue work in the building is slow due to there only being emergency lights
館內為防止漏電引起火災 只能使用緊急照明燈
to prevent fire from electrical leaks.
救援工作進度緩慢
Dr. Fuyuki, Ms. Natsume and Mr. Tokumaru.
冬木醫師、夏梅小姐、德丸先生
Take care of transport and treatment of patients outside.
請幫被救出的傷患 進行治療，並安排送醫
I will take care of the patients still inside.
我去治療裡面的傷患
-Ms. Minh, come with me. -Yes.
-敏小姐，請跟我來 -收到
Let's go.
走吧
It's the MER!
我們是行動急診室的人
I'm going to examine you.
我幫你檢查一下喔
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
-It's the MER. -Number injured is increasing.
-我們是行動急診室的人 -傷患人數持續攀升
What's happened?
狀況如何？
TO1 has made it to the scene and are attending to the patients.
一號緊急車輛已抵達現場 開始醫療行動
Dr. Tsurumaki is acting as chief.
目前由弦卷醫師領隊
Chief Kitami and Dr. Otowa are approaching the scene as well.
喜多見主任 跟音羽統籌官也正趕往現場
With the increased number of injuries, the scale has been raised.
隨著傷患人數增加 已經升級為中規模緊急醫療事件
It's the first time for Dr. Tsurumaki to handle a mid-scale incident alone.
這是弦卷醫師 第一次獨自應對中規模事件
Are you okay, Dr. Hina?
比奈醫師，你沒事吧？
I'm fine. Bring the patients to TO1.
我沒事，送傷患到一號手術室
What happened?
怎麼回事？
We have no footage. We don't know.
館內沒有影像，不知道發生什麼事
Female in her 30s. Resuscitated from cardiac arrest due to abdominal wound.
30多歲女性 因腹部受傷導致心臟停止後恢復意識
We will operate on the patient's abdomen to remove
為了移除異物並修復受損的血管
the protruding object and repair the damaged blood vessels.
必須進行開腹止血手術
Dr. Fuyuki. Insert v-sheath from internal jugular.
冬木醫師，右頸內置入靜脈導引鞘
Ms. Natsume, prepare a laparotomy set with two suction tubes.
夏梅小姐 準備開腹手術器械包及兩條抽吸導管
Mr. Tokumaru, bring the stretcher to the building's entrance.
德丸先生，在入口處準備好推床
Take care of her.
麻煩你們了
Dr. Hina, you're wounded.
比奈醫師，你受傷了嗎？
The lighting fell down while she was giving first aid.
她幫傷患急救時照明設備突然掉下
I'm fine, let's go.
我沒事，快走吧
She needs emergency surgery. Moving her to Risk Management Control.
行動急診室通報 患者需要進行緊急手術
Dr. Tsurumaki has injured her arm.
但弦卷醫師的手臂受傷了
Any doctors who can respond?
有能處理的醫師嗎？
Reinforcements are not here yet. Prioritize transport.
援助還沒到，先安排送醫吧
That will take too long. We're taking her to TO1.
那樣來不及，我們會送到一號手術室
We're inside.
上車了
Straight ahead.
往前…
Just stopping the bleeding is fine.
只要止血就好了
Okay.
好的
Dr. Tsurumaki. Can you do this?
弦卷醫師，沒問題嗎？
Dr. Hina. You can't do it with your arm like that.
比奈醫師，你手臂的傷撐不住的
Dr. Hina. It's a difficult operation.
比奈醫師，這手術很複雜
Just block the aorta with a catheter and proceed with transportation.
先用導管阻斷主動脈，安排送醫吧
Dr. Tsurumaki.
弦卷醫師
There's already massive hemorrhaging inside the abdominal cavity.
腹腔內已經大量出血
She could go into cardiac arrest during transportation.
很有可能在送醫途中心臟停止
I have to do this.
我必須幫她動手術
TO1 open.
一號手術室，開門
A v-sheath has been placed in the right jugular vein.
已經在右頸內置入靜脈導引鞘
I'll take over the stabilization.
由我來扶著吧
I'll make a trauma incision to perform open abdominal surgery.
我要切開腹部，進行止血手術
Scalpel.
手術刀
-Ms. Minh, suction please. -Yes.
-敏小姐，進行抽吸 -是
-Blood pressure has dropped to 76. -Retractor.
-血壓下降到76 -牽引器
-Gauze.
-紗布
Doing a hemostasis on mesentery.
止住腸繫膜的血
-Tweezers.
-鑷子
-Mosquito forceps.
-蚊式止血鉗
Hemostasis complete. Remove it slowly, Ms. Minh.
血止住了，敏小姐，慢慢地拔出來
Yes, I will remove it.
是，我要拔出來了
I will follow up.
我來按住
It's been removed.
拔出來了
-I'll take it. -Thank you.
-交給我 -麻煩你了
Bleeding is increasing.
出血量增加
Suction.
我來抽吸
It has reached the abdominal aorta.
傷到了腹部主動脈
Blood pressure has dropped to 68/36.
血壓下降，高壓68，低壓36
-Blood loss has exceeded 4000. -Ms. Minh, perform compression hemostasis.
-出血量超過4000 -敏小姐，加壓止血
Yes.
是
Mattox Maneuver to excise the left parietal peritoneum.
用馬托斯法切開左後腹膜
Then open and repair the aorta.
打開主動脈並進行修復
-Electric scalpel? -Electric scalpel.
-電刀
Dr. Hina.
比奈醫師
I'm fine.
我沒事
Mr. Tokumaru, O plus packed cells and AB plus FFP, twenty units each.
德丸先生，O型陽性紅血球濃厚液 AB型陽性新鮮冷凍血漿各20單位
Got it.
好的
Dr. Hina. She's bleeding from around the v-sheath.
比奈醫師，靜脈導引鞘附近開始出血
-Two units of calcium gluconate. -Got it.
-注射兩劑葡萄糖酸鈣 -好的
Mr. Tokumaru. Turn up the warm saline.
德丸先生，加大溫暖輸液
Got it.
好的
Ms. Minh, lift here.
敏小姐，這邊抬高
More to the right.
往右一點
-Blood pressure dropped to 56/30. -Blood loss is 5000.
-血壓下降，高壓56，低壓30 -出血量5000
Performing hemostasis on the aorta.
止住主動脈的出血
Kelly clamp.
止血鉗
Dr. Hina.
比奈醫師
I'll take it from here.
交給我吧
Chief Kitami.
喜多見主任
Dr. Fuyuki.
冬木醫師
Circulation is compromised due to severe abdominal hemorrhage.
腹部主動脈損傷 引起大量出血，難以維持體循環
It's an injury to the aorta below the renal artery.
腎動脈下的主動脈損傷
Right. I will block and repair the aorta just below the diaphragm.
是的，我要從橫膈膜下方 阻斷主動脈後進行修復
Dr. Otowa, dissect and block the distal part of the injury.
音羽醫師，剝離及阻斷患處的末梢
Dr. Fuyuki and Ms. Minh, continue the transfusion protocol.
冬木醫師、敏小姐，繼續大量輸血
Tokumaru, use the Cell Saver to return the blood.
德丸，用自體血液回收機回輸失血
Ms. Natsume, prepare continuous 3-0 Prolene.
夏梅小姐 準備好連續的3-0縫合線
Electric scalpel. Thanks.
電刀，謝謝
Starting the dissection. Satinsky.
開始剝離，薩丁斯基鉗
Periphery blocked.
阻斷末梢
Got it. Please bend it more.
好的，彎曲一點
-Cauterizing it. -Please do.
-我來燒灼 -麻煩你了
Stitching now with 3-0.
進行縫合，3-0縫合線
I'll assist with the thread. Forceps.
我來協助縫合，鑷子
Please proceed.
麻煩你了
Stitched. Let's remove the Satinsky.
縫合完畢，要鬆開薩丁斯基鉗了
On three, slowly.
數到三一起慢慢鬆開
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Released.
鬆開了
The bleeding has stopped.
血止住了
Blood pressure, 82/58.
高壓82，低壓58
Still rising.
還在上升中
Let's apply an incised drape and temporarily close for transport.
蓋上手術巾，暫時關腹後安排送醫
Yes.
是
All rescue and transport of the injured are complete.
所有傷患都已獲得救助並送醫
For this dispatch, 15 minor injuries, three serious.
本次出動，輕傷15人，重傷3人
And casualties…
死亡人數…
Zero!
零
For Dr. Tsurumaki to get injured just as Dr. Otowa is leaving is problematic.
音羽醫師就快離隊 弦卷醫師又受傷了，這樣不太妙吧
That Ministry of Health geezer will be on our case.
厚勞省的老頭要找我們麻煩了
If we hadn't arrived, the patient would have died.
要是我們沒趕到，患者就沒命了
Did you not think to block the aorta and transfer her
難道你沒想到 你這種傷勢無法進行手術
when you have an injury that made it impossible for you to operate?
先用導管阻斷主動脈 並安排送醫是更妥當的做法嗎？
It's my responsibility.
都是我的錯
I should have properly checked Dr. Hina's condition and insisted more strongly.
我應該好好確認比奈醫師的傷勢 更堅決地提出建議
No.
不
As the doctor in charge of the scene,
身為負責現場的醫生
I judged that I could perform the hemostasis.
我認為我能應付腹腔內止血的手術
But you couldn't handle the injury to the abdominal aorta.
但沒料到 傷到了腹部主動脈，你應付不來
The old Dr. Hina would have given up from the start.
換作是以前的比奈醫師 一開始就放棄了
Now, she is courageously trying to save patients.
但現在的她會鼓起勇氣去救人
Reckless courage without skill is most dangerous.
最危險的就是有勇無謀還沒實力的人
Saying it like that is…
怎麼說這種話？
Dr. Hina's efforts saved the patient.
是比奈醫師盡了全力，患者才獲救的
Chief Kitami, what do you think about Dr. Hina's decision?
喜多見主任 對於比奈醫師這次的判斷你怎麼看？
The inability to control blood loss upon opening the aorta was foreseeable,
一旦打開主動脈 出血狀況就會難以控制
considering the amount of blood suctioned and the case's progress.
這一點是可以從 抽吸出的血量及手術過程預測到的
A doctor in charge of the scene cannot overlook this.
負責現場的醫生絕對不能忽視這一點
Insisting on operating with an injured arm was an error in judgment by Dr. Hina.
手臂受傷還堅持動手術 是比奈醫師的判斷失誤
I'm sorry.
對不起
Once you finish your residency,
比奈醫師，你在研修結束後
you should pursue cardiovascular surgery, Dr. Hina.
應該加入心臟血管外科
This is my last piece of advice before leaving the team.
這是我在離隊之前最後的建議
It is crucial for doctors responding to accidents or disasters
避免趕往事故現場的醫師 受到二次傷害
that they avoid involvement in secondary disasters.
這是至關重要的事
Moreover, Dr. Tsurumaki attempted to operate with an injured arm.
而且弦卷醫師手臂受傷卻堅持動手術
She put the patient's life at risk.
這是將患者的生命置於危險之中
Dr. Kitami, what are your thoughts on this situation?
喜多見醫師 你對於這件事有什麼看法？
Everything is my responsibility as the team leader.
身為團隊領導人，我責無旁貸
I apologize for causing all this trouble.
給大家添麻煩了，真的非常抱歉
Dr. Tsurumaki could have lost her life.
要是有什麼萬一 弦卷醫師可能會連命都丟了
We can't lend any more residents
我們不能再允許住院醫生
to a team involved in such dangerous medical activities.
加入這個團隊 參與如此危險的醫療行動
Dr. Tsurumaki's initial residency is about to end, right?
弦卷醫師的初期臨床研修 就快結束了吧？
Yes.
是的
Is your intention still to specialize in cardiovascular surgery?
你還是像當初那樣 打算專攻心臟血管外科嗎？
I want to continue studying cardiovascular surgery
我想繼續在 心臟血管外科的高輪醫師手下學習
under Dr. Takanawa. That has not changed.
這個想法並沒有改變
Understood. Also, Dr. Kitami.
好的，喜多見醫師
Dr. Otowa will soon leave the team
音羽醫師不久後也會離開團隊
to focus on his MER supervisory role, correct?
以專注於 行動急診室統籌官的工作，對吧？
Right. We need to decide on a new second doctor.
是的，我們必須委任新的副手醫師了
What are your plans?
你有什麼打算？
Does anyone here want to be my second doctor?
這裡有人願意當我的副手醫師嗎？
Our hospital has never had the luxury of surplus staff.
我們醫院本來就人手不足
If you are unable to establish a proper medical system,
如果無法建立起完善的醫療體系
it might be better to consult Governor Akatsuka
最好還是跟赤塚知事商量一下
and transfer you to a university hospital.
讓你轉到大學醫院
Wait a minute. If that happens, the current team…
不，請等一下，那其他成員怎麼辦？
They are originally our medical staff.
他們原本就是我們的醫療人員
The current team will be dissolved,
現在只能解散團隊
and we will have to gather new staff at the next institution.
在下一家醫院招攬新的醫療人員
Minister Kamata whom you're about to meet
待會要見的蒲田大臣
is no less tricky than the former Minister Shirokane.
跟前任的白金大臣相比 是有過之無不及的麻煩人物
Don't fall for any traps he might set.
千萬不要掉進他的圈套
Do you dislike this Minister Kamata?
你不喜歡這位蒲田大臣啊？
I don't dislike him.
不是不喜歡
I hate him.
是超級討厭
He's a greedy old man who only thinks about money.
他是個滿腦子都是錢的貪財老頭
The Ministry of Health plans to deploy MERs to all major cities,
除了直屬於都知事的東京行動急診室
and not only the Tokyo MER directly under the Metropolitan Governor.
厚勞省打算 在全國各大都市部署行動急診室
This plan is finally starting. You're aware of that, aren't you?
這項計畫終於要開始了 你知道這件事吧？
Yes, of course.
是，我知道
I am worried though.
不過，我有點擔心
It must worry you quite a bit that Otowa's replacement hasn't been found yet.
接替音羽副手醫師職務的人選 還沒定好，想必你一定很煩惱吧
Thank you for your concern.
多謝您的關心
The reason I called you today
我今天找你們來不為別的
is to introduce a talented individual from the Ministry
是為了拯救東京行動急診室的危機
to help save the crisis at Tokyo MER.
給你們介紹一位厚勞省的優秀人才
Aoto.
青戶
I am Tatsuya Aoto from the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare.
我是厚勞省醫政局總務課的青戶達也
Aoto is one of my subordinates.
青戶是我的下屬
Like Otowa, he is a medical official with a medical license.
跟音羽一樣 是擁有醫師執照的醫療技官
How about considering him for the second doctor role?
不嫌棄的話 可以考慮讓他擔任副手醫師
Of course, the decision is up to Governor Akatsuka and Mr. Kitami.
當然了，這件事完全交給 赤塚知事跟喜多見先生決定
We appreciate the kind offer,
非常感謝您的推薦
but doesn't being a medical official mean
但醫療技官的話
you have been away from practical medicine for a while?
應該已經有一段時間 沒參與醫療工作了吧？
Rest assured.
請放心
Until eight years ago, I was a practicing doctor in a hospital.
一直到八年前，我都在醫院裡行醫
Eight years ago?
八年前？
After joining here, I've participated in medical support during disasters,
進入厚勞省後 我也曾在災害發生時參與醫療援助
and above all,
更何況
if Otowa could do it, so can I.
音羽做得到的話，我也能做到
Excuse me for being blunt, but why did you get a medical license?
不好意思，冒昧問一下 你為什麼要考醫師執照呢？
Of course,
當然是因為
it's because I want to save people's lives.
我想拯救生命
I see.
我明白了
In that case, could you help me as my support doctor?
那可以請你擔任我的副手醫師嗎？
Kitami!
喜多見
I look forward to working with you, Chief Kitami.
請多指教，喜多見主任
working with you too, Dr. Aoto.
也請你多多指教，青戶醫師
I'm glad to have been of help.
能幫上忙真是太好了
Now, Aoto, please discuss future plans with Chief Kitami.
青戶，那你就趕緊 跟喜多見主任探討今後的工作吧
I will do my best to meet your expectations, Minister Kamata.
我會盡最大的努力，不負您的期望
-Let us go. -Excuse us.
-走吧 -告辭
Excuse us.
告辭
Why Mr. Aoto?
為什麼是青戶？
I know what you want to say.
我知道你想說什麼
He graduated from a third-rate university, was useless in the hospital,
青戶是三流大學出身 在醫院裡完全派不上用場
and used his parents' connections to flee here. He's a complete dud.
是個靠父母的關係躲到這裡的廢物
His parents lost the last election, so now he can't use them anymore.
他父母在上次選舉中落選了 已經沒有利用價值了
So why…
那為什麼…
It's precisely because he is a dud.
就因為是廢物才好呢
You are hoping that Mr. Aoto will fail?
您是希望青戶先生出現失誤嗎？
Before expanding MER nationwide,
在將行動急診室擴展到全國各地之前
Minister Kamata intends to dismantle the Tokyo MER under the governor.
蒲田大臣打算先解散 直屬於都知事的東京行動急診室
Then, the Ministry of Health can rebuild the entire MER system from scratch.
這樣一來，厚勞省就能 從頭開始重建行動急診室的體系
You will have free rein over the national MER network.
你也可以自由地 掌管全國的行動急診室
Mr. Kugayama. Have you completed the list of medical equipment makers
久我山局長 參與行動急診室全國擴展計畫的
who will be involved in the national MER expansion plan?
醫療器械製造商名單都做好了嗎？
Here it is.
在這裡
What is the number?
對方給什麼數字？
It's 10%.
百分之十
You sure are competent.
你滿能幹的嘛
Ms. Shirokane was right in recognizing your talent.
不愧是白金認可的男人
Thank you.
你過獎了
Are you changing suppliers?
您要更換廠商嗎？
The current ones are well-versed in MER operations and have expertise.
目前合作的廠商具備專業知識 也熟知行動急診室的運作方式
Long-term relationships can get too cozy.
合作得越久，越容易互相勾結
We need fresh blood.
得注入新血才行呢
I wasn't informed about this change.
我沒聽說更換廠商的事
It's the minister's decision.
這是蒲田大臣的決定
We will gain nothing from changing.
更換廠商一點好處也沒有
With the existing know-how, we can produce ER cars suited for emergencies.
現有廠商可以用累積下來的經驗 製造出更適合緊急醫療用的急診車
You are so naive.
你在說什麼傻話呢？
You know, don't you?
你也很清楚吧？
New entrants will donate 10% of profits
新加入的廠商會將百分之十的利潤
as a rebate to Minister Kamata's political group.
捐贈給蒲田大臣的政治團體作為回扣
Will you leak it to the media?
你要爆料給媒體嗎？
The expansion of MER will stall, and you as supervisor will be out too.
行動急診室全國擴展計畫被擱置的話 作為統籌官的你也難辭其咎
You can't realize ideals with empty words.
一清如水是無法實現理想的
As a bureaucrat, one must navigate both the clear and murky waters.
清濁並包、善惡兼容才是官員的本色
Thank you so much for everything.
非常感謝各位的關照
This is the address of our restaurant.
這是我家的餐廳
If you're ever in the neighborhood, please come and eat.
如果碰巧在附近，歡迎過來吃東西
It's on the house.
我請客
Thank you very much.
謝謝你
Is it named after Kurumi?
是以胡桃的名字命名的嗎？
It's in Asakusa, I see.
在淺草啊
I'll make sure to come by.
我一定會去光顧的
Thank you so much.
謝謝大家
Dr. Hina, this is for you.
比奈醫師，這送你
THANK YOU, DR. HINA KURUMI
（比奈醫師，謝謝你，胡桃）
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll treasure this.
我會珍藏的
Bye-bye, Dr. Hina.
比奈醫師，拜拜
-Bye-bye. -Thank you.
-拜拜 -謝謝
You made the right choice to stay in cardiovascular surgery.
留在心臟血管外科是正確的選擇喔
Huh?
什麼？
I know that you worked hard in the MER,
我知道你在行動急診室工作很拼命
and what you learned there won't be wasted.
你在那裡學到的東西也不會白費
You can use that as a cardiovascular surgeon.
可以在心臟血管外科派上用場啊
You're right.
說的也是
I have officially become a member of Tokyo MER from today.
我是從今天開始 正式成為東京行動急診室成員的
I am Tatsuya Aoto.
青戶達也
Although I've been away from the medical field for a while,
雖然我離開醫療前線已經有一段時間
the skills and knowledge I learned during my days with patients
但與病患相處時學到的技術和知識
are not easily forgotten.
是不會輕易被忘記的
I look forward to saving many lives with you all.
我想跟大家一起拯救更多的生命
Thank you very much.
請多多關照
And now, our new official member Dr. Aoto,
那麼，青戶醫師 就正式成為我們的一員了
if you would please proceed with the locker naming ceremony.
請進行置物櫃姓名標記儀式
Thank you.
請多關照
Dr. Aoto.
青戶醫師
-It's great that he's a cheerful person. -Yes.
-看來是個開朗的人，太好了呢 -是啊
I heard he was a medical official,
聽說是醫療技官
so I worried he'd be difficult like Dr. Otowa.
我還擔心他會像音羽醫師那樣難搞呢
Ah, sorry.
抱歉
Are you the intern, Ms. Hina Tsurumaki?
你是住院醫生弦卷比奈小姐嗎？
Yes.
是的
I heard you're graduating from MER to join cardiovascular surgery.
我聽說你會離開行動急診室 到心臟血管外科服務
Good job.
辛苦了
It must have been tough.
一定很艱難吧
Even though you're an intern unfamiliar with everything,
明明還是個不熟悉工作的住院醫生
you engaged yourself in such a high-risk field of medicine.
卻要前往高風險的醫療現場
It reminds me of my days as an intern.
讓我想起自己還是住院醫生的時光呢
I would choose cardiovascular surgery over such a dangerous job, too.
比起這麼危險的工作 果然還是選擇心臟血管外科更好吧
What has been going on so far?
之前的出動都是怎麼樣的呢？
-Chief Kitami. -Yes.
-喜多見主任 -是
Are you sure about letting Dr. Hina go like this?
你真的就這樣讓比奈醫師離隊嗎？
The entire hospital expects her to go to cardiovascular surgery.
院方已經想著要她去心臟血管外科了
If you're going to stop it, now's the time.
事不宜遲，要阻止的話只能趁現在了
Dr. Aoto, I'll show you the materials in the staff room.
青戶醫師 我給你介紹一下員工室的器材
Please.
麻煩你了
Syringe pumps are on both sides, and for infusions…
注射幫浦在這兩邊，點滴的話在…
He ran away.
逃走了
Well, it's her decision,
算了，這是她本人的決定
and we should continue to work together as a team for our patients.
我們還是一如既往 為了病患團結一心，並肩同行吧
Okay.
-好吧
Huh?
嗯？
Dr. Otowa.
音羽醫師
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦了
What is it? If you have something to say, please say it quickly.
怎麼了？有什麼想說的就趕緊說吧
Originally…
原本…
my dream was to become a cardiac surgeon just like Dr. Takanawa.
我想跟高輪醫師一樣 成為一名心臟血管外科醫生
I really hated being assigned to MER just to fill numbers.
當初為了湊人數被分派到行動急診室 我真的是心不甘情不願
I couldn't believe doctors had to work in dangerous places.
醫師居然要在危險的現場行醫
It baffled me.
這種事簡直難以置信
I can't, I'm an intern. I might make a mistake again.
我只是住院醫生 我辦不到，說不定又會出錯的
Stop making excuses!
不要再找藉口了
You're a doctor. Save these people.
是醫生的話，就給我盡全力救人
But I learned that some lives could not be saved if I just waited.
但我明白了如果只是在原地等待 也許會錯失拯救生命的機會
I felt that maybe even I could do something.
我覺得就算是這樣的我 或許也有力所能及的事
I'm glad you were there.
還好當時有你在
Thank you.
謝謝你
While experiencing the field with everyone,
跟大家一起在現場累積經驗的過程中
I began to take pride in my work at MER.
我開始對行動急診室的工作感到自豪
I thought I wanted to…
我很想就這樣
continue working with everyone at MER.
一直跟行動急診室的夥伴們一起工作
But…
但是…
the more I learned about the field, the more scared I became.
越了解現場，我就感到越害怕
If I stayed,
如果我留下來
I would eventually become the second doctor
我總有一天會成為副手醫師
and support Dr. Kitami.
然後協助喜多見主任
But I just couldn't imagine myself replacing you, Dr. Otowa.
但我無法想像 自己能取代音羽醫師你的位置
In other words, you're in doubt?
也就是說，你很迷茫嗎？
Is it…
我有能力…
impossible for me to be MER's second doctor?
成為行動急診室的副手醫師嗎？
I don't know what answer you're seeking,
我不知道你希望我如何回答
but the job cannot go to someone who lacks confidence.
但沒有自信的人無法勝任這份工作
In this field,
在我們出動的現場
if a doctor hesitates for even a moment, it can cost the life of a patient.
一旦醫師有一瞬間的迷茫 患者就有可能失去生命
Risk Management Control.
都廳危機管理對策室通報
A houseboat has collided with a water bus on the Sumida River.
航行在隅田川的 一艘屋形船跟一艘大型水上巴士相撞
There's a fire in the houseboat's kitchen with multiple reported injured.
屋形船的廚房起火 船內有多名人員受傷
It's a large-scale medical emergency. Requesting Tokyo MER.
判定為大規模緊急醫療事件 請求東京行動急診室出動
Copy that. On our way.
收到，立即出動
Ms. Natsume, Ms. Minh. Prep suture sets in case of trauma and airway injuries.
夏梅小姐、敏小姐 準備呼吸道灼傷和外傷的手術器械包
Bring extra oxygen and warm saline solution.
-多準備一些氧氣和溫暖輸液 -收到
Dr. Fuyuki and Tokumaru, set up the OR in case of emergency.
冬木醫師、德丸 以防萬一，提前準備好手術室
We'll bring extra tools and blood for transfusions.
我們會多帶一些輸血和手術用的器材
Large-scale medical emergency?
大規模緊急醫療事件？
Dr. Aoto, let's bring extra intubation sets.
青戶醫師，多拿一些插管急救組
Oh, right. Uh…
是，那個…
-Here. -Oh.
-在這裡 -好
I'll go too.
我也去
Your arm hasn't healed yet. Stay at the hospital.
你的手臂還沒好，留在醫院吧
-Let's go. -Yes!
-出發 -是
The houseboat's engine is still running, heading towards the estuary.
屋形船的引擎還沒熄火，正駛向河口
It has passed Komagata Bridge, moving towards Kuramae Bridge.
剛通過駒形橋，往藏前橋的方向移動
According to the crew, the steering room is damaged by the fire.
據船員通報，火災導致駕駛室損壞
The boat is out of control and running wild.
船隻失控，正在疾馳
Copy that. We'll head farther downstream.
收到，我們會前往更下游
We'll go ahead to Ryogoku Bridge to check first.
在兩國橋待命，進行確認
Status on rescue operation?
救援行動的狀況如何？
Fire boats dispatched from the harbor and Nihonbashi Fire Station.
消防廳臨港消防署 跟日本橋消防署派出了消防船
The firefighters seem to have extinguished the fire.
雖然火勢已撲滅
However, it is challenging to rescue passengers from the moving boat.
但由於船隻無法停止 所以難以救出船內的傷患
I'll go check it out.
我去看一下
This is Kitami. Boat spotted near Ryogoku Bridge.
我是喜多見 在兩國橋前發現船隻的蹤影
What's the status inside?
船內狀況如何？
Details are still unclear, but there are 45 passengers and crew members.
具體情況不明 只知道有45名乘客和船員
The captain is injured and in critical condition, unconscious.
船長受傷，意識不清，病況危急
The combination of low tide and last night's heavy rain upstream
由於昨晚上游下大雨，又趕上退潮
caused the boat's speed to increase.
導致船隻加速
Many passengers are panicking outside.
船外有多名驚慌的乘客
The rescue boats cannot dock alongside so rescue efforts are not proceeding.
目前救援船難以靠近 無法進行救援行動
Hey! Hey, are we going to crash?
欸…是不是快撞上去了？
Mr. Komaba. It'll hit the bridge girder at this rate.
駒場先生 再這樣下去船隻就要撞上橋梁了
Where are the rescue boats?!
救援船呢？
They can't dock. We can't get to them in time!
他們靠近不了，無法接應
Hurry!
快來啊
Chief Kitami, the boat is likely to break and sink.
喜多見主任 船隻極有可能遭撞毀下沉
Prepare medical teams anticipating several water rescue victims.
組建醫療小隊 準備應付多名從水中救出的傷患
Got it.
收到
People pulled from the river will be treated at the base of Ryogoku Bridge.
從河裡救上來的傷患 就在兩國橋的底部進行緊急處理
Urgently select a first aid space and call for reinforcements.
請盡快設置急救場所 呼叫周邊的醫療機關前來支援
Wait.
等等
Mr. Senju.
千住隊長
This is Senju from the Rescue Squad.
我是即刻救援部隊的千住
We'll board the houseboat and attempt to prevent a collision by towing.
我們將登上屋形船 嘗試透過拖曳來防止衝撞
Don't lean out!
不要出來
Don't jump off the boat! You could be run over!
請不要跳船，會被碾過去的
Help us!
救救我們
-Clear to board! -Boarding!
-可以了 -上船
-Coming through! -You'll be okay!
-麻煩借過 -沒事的
We are the rescue squad. You're safe now.
我們是救難隊，請放心
Hurry up and help us!
快救救我們
We'll control the ship first. Secure the bow with ropes.
首先要控制船隻，用繩子固定船頭
Tow with the fireboat.
交給消防船拖曳
Roger!
收到
Sending throw bag!
接好拋繩袋
Throw bag received!
接到了
Everything's okay now.
沒事的
Hurry, the bridge is close!
動作快，就快撞上去了
It's tied!
綁好了
Connection made! Starting to tow the boat!
綁好了，開始拖曳
Got it!
收到
The current is good.
狀況良好
It's going to be a bit shaky.
會有點搖晃喔
This is Senju. We're passing Ryogoku Bridge.
我是千住，安全通過兩國橋了
This is Kitami. Chasing the ship with TO1, heading downstream.
我是喜多見 一號緊急車輛會跟隨屋形船到下游
Please direct us to the rendezvous point.
請指示與救難隊會合的地點
Okay.
好的
We're the rescue squad.
我們是救難隊
We will get you out of here.
現在救你們出去
Please move to the front of the boat so everyone can get off quickly.
為了盡快救出所有人，請移至船頭
Give them life jackets and keep them from falling overboard.
讓他們穿好救生衣，以防他們掉下水
Yes!
是
Senju, what's the situation inside?
千住，船內狀況如何？
It's full of smoke, low visibility.
船內有煙，能見度低
The smoke is…
煙是…
Still billowing from the bottom of the ship.
正從船底冒出來
Seems like there's a fire at the bottom of the ship.
看來船底有起火
A fire at the bottom?
船底起火？
It's usually non-flammable, so this shouldn't be happening.
船底通常是不可燃的，不會起火
Perhaps something flammable was left behind by mistake.
可能不小心放了可燃物，忘了拿出來
Over ten people with visible injuries, including burns and trauma.
可見範圍內至少有十人有燒傷和外傷
The explosion occurred in the rear kitchen.
爆炸發生在船尾的廚房
Seems to have been caused by a gas cylinder.
應該是煤氣瓶著火導致的
The wheelhouse next to it is damaged. Steering is impossible.
旁邊的駕駛室受損，無法操控船隻
Can you stop the engine?
能關閉引擎嗎？
Where is the engine room?
引擎室在哪裡？
-Under the floor there. -Thank you.
-那邊的地板下面 -謝謝
Do you have the key?
有鑰匙嗎？
Only the captain knows where it is.
只有船長知道鑰匙放哪
Captain, are you okay?
船長，你還好嗎？
Stopping the engine may be difficult.
要關閉引擎恐怕很困難
And the fire?
火災呢？
I think it started in the engine room at the bottom,
起火點估計在船底的引擎室
but not sure we can extinguish it.
很難直接滅火
The only way is to flood it with water, but that risks sinking the ship.
唯一的辦法就是往船底 灌入大量的水，但那樣會導致沉船
We have to evacuate the passengers first.
必須先疏散船上所有的人
But the fuel tanks are down there.
但是，船底有燃料箱
Yes.
是的
This ship will eventually explode.
這艘船遲早會爆炸
We cannot dock a ship that won't stop.
失控的船隻無法靠岸
Can you use the life and rescue boats to evacuate the people on board?
能不能用救生艇和消防船 將全體乘客和船員疏散到岸邊？
We will!
沒問題
The evacuation point will be the Hakozaki Disaster Prevention Pier.
疏散點定在下游兩公里處的 箱崎町防災船停泊處
Coordinate with fire station and police and have emergency vehicles on standby.
跟消防廳和警方協調 並安排緊急車輛待命
Roger!
收到
Oh my. This is a serious situation.
天啊，這可真是場大事故呢
Minister Kamata.
蒲田大臣
I've come to observe with the nationwide deployment of MER in mind.
我正在為行動急診室 全國擴展計畫進行視察
Please don't mind me.
不用管我
Where's the dud?
那個廢物呢？
He has been dispatched.
跟著出動了
This will be a sight to behold.
這下有看頭了啊
The next person can change boats, slowly.
下一位請準備換乘，慢慢來
Mr. Senju, this is Kitami.
千住隊長，我是喜多見
Can you send us footage from inside the ship?
可以把船內的影像傳送給我們嗎？
It's an emergency, so we'll triage using the video.
我們想爭分奪秒 先透過影像做檢傷分類
-Got it. -Sharing the footage.
-好的 -分享現場影像
Thank you.
謝謝
The woman in yellow clothes by the wall, how are her pulse and breathing?
靠牆的那位黃衣女性 她的脈搏和呼吸怎麼樣？
Deformation and swelling on the right knee.
右膝變形和腫脹
She's conscious and breathing clearly, but her pulse is weakening,
意識清晰，呼吸正常 但脈搏正在變弱
That would be a red tag.
她是紅色
If there's no external bleeding, fix her leg with a splint
如果沒有外出血，用副木固定右下腿
and elevate both legs a bit when transporting her.
運送出去的時候稍微抬高她的雙腿
-Got it. -Next person, please.
-好的 -下一位
The patient lying down there with soot on his face.
那位癱倒在地、臉上沾滿煙灰的傷患
Charring on the face or airway could mean thermal injury to the airway.
如果臉部或呼吸道有灼傷 那氣道有可能被燒傷
Elevate his upper body and be aware of suffocation. Give him a yellow tag.
讓他坐起來 注意不要讓他窒息，他是黃色
-Prepare more fluids for infusion. -We'll add more splints as well.
-多準備一些輸液 -還有副木
The man who is holding his stomach, are there any contusions on the abdomen?
按著肚子的那位男性 他的腹部有挫傷嗎？
I'll lift here. Yes, there are.
我要拉高你的襯衫喔，有的
Please give him a yellow tag.
他是黃色
Don't let him walk as it might worsen the injury.
不要讓他走動，免得傷勢惡化
A yellow tag.
她是黃色
She's panicking, so make her take slow breaths and calm her down.
她恐慌發作 讓她緩慢地深呼吸，冷靜下來
A red tag. Check in on her periodically.
她是紅色，需要定時確認她的情況
Is the person next to her a friend?
她身邊那位是她的朋友吧？
Let them know to keep talking to her.
請交代他要不斷地跟她說話
This is the captain.
這位是船長
Can you check pulse and breathing?
可以檢查他的脈搏和呼吸嗎？
Unresponsive with an injury on his head,
他因右側頭部外傷陷入昏迷
laceration from right ear to neck and heavy bleeding from the nose.
右耳到頸部有撕裂傷 鼻子也大量出血
-Pulse and breathing is weakening. -That's a critical condition, a red tag.
-脈搏和呼吸越來越弱 -是紅色分類的危險情況
Please prioritize transporting the captain first.
請優先將船長運送出來
We'll operate on the head injury at TO1.
我們要在一號手術室進行頭頸部手術
Protect his spine during transport.
在運送過程中注意頸椎保護
Got it.
好的
Next one, please.
下一位
Mr. Senju!
千住隊長
Show us the parent and child.
請看一看那對母女
Ms. Natsume, those two…
夏梅小姐，這兩位…
It's Kurumi and her mother?
是胡桃和她媽媽
Do you know them?
你們認識嗎？
Kurumi is a patient of Dr. Takanawa.
胡桃是高輪醫師的病患
She has pulmonary atresia and a ventricular defect.
她患有肺動脈閉鎖合併心室中膈缺損
She had a Rastelli procedure and was discharged recently.
最近剛做完 右心室肺動脈外通道手術後出院
Are they conscious?
她們意識清晰嗎？
The mother's name is Maki Kyobashi.
母親的名字是京橋真紀
This is the rescue squad.
我是救難隊的人
Ms. Maki, Kurumi. Are you okay?
真紀小姐、胡桃，你們還好嗎？
Ms. Maki. Ms. Maki, are you okay?
真紀小姐…你還好嗎？
My daughter…
我女兒…
Ms. Maki. Ms. Maki!
真紀小姐…
This is Tsurumaki. Please share the video of Kurumi to the staff room.
我是弦卷 請將胡桃的影像分享到員工室
I'm sharing it.
正在分享
Mr. Senju, is there any bleeding in the chest area?
千住隊長，胸部有出血嗎？
There's bleeding.
有
Don't move her!
請不要動她
She may be bleeding from the artificial blood vessel.
可能是從人工血管流出來的
Dr. Hina, where is Dr. Takanawa?
比奈醫師，高輪醫師在哪？
She's in surgery.
她在動手術
Can you bring a wire twister here?
你能把鋼線持針器拿過來嗎？
I'm on my way.
我馬上過去
What should we do?
現在該怎麼做？
Don't move them. The vascular laceration could worsen.
為免擴大血管的破裂，先不要移動她
The mother has a severe head injury and is unconscious.
母親有嚴重的頭部外傷，失去意識
A spinal cord injury could lead to paralysis or respiratory arrest,
若頸髓受傷 可能會導致癱瘓及呼吸停止
so keep her still.
所以也請不要移動
But if we do nothing…
但放著不管的話…
I'll go there.
我會過去
What are you saying? It's going to explode.
你說什麼呢？那艘船快爆炸了
-Chief Kitami. -I have to go to save them.
-喜多見主任 -要是我不去，就救不了她們了
Bring Chief Kitami to the boat.
讓喜多見主任上船
Senju, secure an emergency lifeboat to Hakozaki Disaster Prevention Pier.
千住，準備一艘救生艇 停在箱崎町防災船停泊處
Roger!
收到
I'll head to the houseboat when we arrive.
一抵達那裡，我會直接上屋形船
Ms. Minh and Dr. Aoto, transport the captain to TO1.
敏小姐、青戶醫師 你們將船長送來一號手術室
Dr. Otowa and Dr. Aoto, proceed with the surgery on his head.
由音羽醫師和青戶醫師 負責右側頭頸部的手術
Ms. Natsume, prep the tools.
夏梅小姐，你來遞器械
Dr. Fuyuki, prepare for general anesthesia.
冬木醫師，準備施行全身麻醉
-Tokumaru, standby on SL1. -Understood.
-德丸，準備好輸血輸液加溫器 -收到
Dr. Otowa, I leave the rest to you.
音羽醫師，接下來就拜託你了
MER has arrived at Hakozaki.
行動急診室已抵達箱崎町
-Dr. Aoto, please start from the bottom. -Yes.
-青戶醫師，拜託你往下抬 -好
Take the children to the shore first…
先把孩子們送到岸邊
Ma'am, wait a moment please.
這位媽媽，請稍等一下
It's scary, but you'll be fine.
雖然很可怕，但沒事的
Dr. Kitami, over here!
喜多見醫師，這邊
Mr. Tatsumi.
辰巳先生
He's on board. Stern okay, bow okay.
上船了，船尾沒問題，船頭沒問題
Setting off.
-開船
The captain is here.
船長在這裡
Yes.
好
One, two, three. Please.
一、二、三，麻煩了
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
-What happened? -Are you okay?
-怎麼了？ -你還好嗎？
Dr. Otowa, another patient aside from the captain
音羽醫師，船長這邊有另一名患者
might have a chest trauma.
疑似有胸部外傷
He has contusions on the left anterior chest.
左前胸有挫傷的痕跡
He's barely conscious, showing signs of shock.
意識模糊，處於休克狀態
Understood. I'll head to the medical tent.
我知道了，我馬上過去醫療帳篷
Please bring this patient to the medical tent.
-請將這名患者送到醫療帳篷 -是
Yes. Please!
麻煩了
Dr. Aoto, transport the captain to TO1.
青戶醫師，將船長送到一號手術室
Got it.
好的
Take my hand!
抓住我的手
-Where is Kurumi and her mom? -This way.
-胡桃和她媽媽呢？ -這邊
We evacuated everybody else.
其他人都已經疏散了
Mr. Minato, Mr. Kosuge, give them oxygen.
湊先生、小菅先生，給她們供氧
Yes!
收到
I'm Dr. Kitami, can you hear me?
我是喜多見醫師，聽得到我說話嗎？
Kurumi, can you hear me?
胡桃，聽得到我說話嗎？
Ma'am! Ms. Maki, can you hear me?
這位媽媽 真紀小姐，聽得到我說話嗎？
I'm leaning in here.
我幫你檢查一下喔
What's the situation?
狀況如何？
Kurumi might have bleeding around the heart.
胡桃的心臟周圍可能有出血
The mother may have respiratory issues due to suspected spinal injury,
她媽媽疑似頸髓受傷導致呼吸不順暢
so I'll intubate her here and protect the spine during transport.
我在這裡幫她插管 再護著頸椎運送出去
I'll help. Instruct me.
我來幫忙，下指示吧
Okay. Please attach the monitor.
好，請幫她接心電圖
Hang in there, Kurumi.
胡桃，加油喔
Let's do this together.
一起加油
Dr. Otowa, there's an arrhythmia.
音羽醫師，出現心律不整
Blood pressure, 76/42.
高壓76，低壓42
Otowa.
音羽
Surgery prep is ready in TO1, come back immediately.
一號手術室的手術準備 已經完成，馬上回來
I can't leave now.
我現在離不開
-Ligate the facial arteries. -But--
-麻煩你進行臉部動脈結紮 -但是…
Right now, you're the only one who can save the patient.
現在能救那個患者的人只有你
TO1 open.
一號手術室，開門
We will now begin the surgery for the head and neck injury.
現在開始右側頭頸部外傷手術
-Dr. Fuyuki. General anesthesia. -Yes.
-冬木醫師，全身麻醉 -是
-Ms. Natsume, tools.
-夏梅小姐，遞器械
Mr. Tokumaru, prep the electric scalpel.
德丸先生，準備電刀
Yes.
是
Governor Akatsuka, is it really okay to make Aoto the lead surgeon?
什麼？一上來就讓青戶主刀？ 這樣好嗎，赤塚知事？
It's an emergency, we have no choice.
現在情況緊急，我們別無他法
He's been away from practical medicine for so long,
但他已經離開醫療前線很長時間了
I don't agree with it.
我反對
If anything happens, it's not on me.
要是出什麼事，我可不管喔
As long as Tokyo MER is under the governor's direct control,
只要東京行動急診室 還是直屬於都知事
I take full responsibility.
就由我全權負責
-Scalpel.
-手術刀
Dr. Aoto, here's the gauze.
青戶醫師，紗布
You'll need suction, right?
需要抽吸，對吧？
Yes.
是的
Can you control the bleeding?
能止住出血嗎？
It's hard to see.
看不清楚
Should we expand the other side?
要拉開另一邊嗎？
Please do.
麻煩你了
Blood pressure dropped to 60/42.
血壓下降，高壓60，低壓42
Applying pressure to control bleeding.
我來加壓止血
Preparing the Cell Saver.
我準備自體血液回收機
Dr. Aoto, please identify the source of the bleeding.
青戶醫師，請確認出血點
I know.
我知道
He's even more of a dud than I imagined.
比我想像的更廢物啊
Yes.
是啊
Dr. Aoto, the source of bleeding?
青戶醫師，請確認出血點
Blood pressure dropping further, 54/38.
血壓更低了，高壓54，低壓38
Dr. Aoto.
青戶醫師
I can't do it.
不行
This is too much too soon.
一下要做這麼難的手術
I can't do this!
我辦不到
Identify the source of bleeding and control the artery!
找出出血點，然後止住動脈的出血
You are a doctor, only you can do it!
這裡只有身為醫生的你才辦得到
Dr. Aoto!
青戶醫師
Electric scalpel.
電刀
I'll take it from here.
交給我吧
It's from the external carotid artery system.
出血點在外頸動脈
Severe hemorrhagic shock with a risk of cardiac arrest.
重度出血性休克，可能導致心臟停止
I'll ligate the external carotid through a right submandibular incision.
夏梅小姐，我要切開右下頜 阻斷外頸動脈的末端
I'll assist with suction.
好的，我來幫忙抽吸
Thank you. Mr. Tokumaru,
麻煩了，德丸先生
warm the transfusion with SL1 and switch to rapid infusion.
用加溫器加溫輸液，加大輸液流速
Dr. Fuyuki, can you maintain circulation?
冬木醫師，可以維持體循環嗎？
-I'll correct the coagulation as well. -Thank you.
-我也會調整凝血功能 -麻煩了
-Artery visible, need a hemostatic clip. -Here.
-找到動脈了，止血夾 -是
Got it.
我拿到了
Ligated. What's the blood pressure?
阻斷血流了，血壓多少？
72/50, it's rising.
高壓72，低壓50，上升中
Let's ligate the facial artery peripherally.
現在進行臉部動脈結紮
Ms. Natsume, mosquito clamp.
夏梅小姐，蚊式止血鉗
-3-0 silk suture. -3-0.
-3-0縫合線 -3-0
Blood pressure rising further, stable at 84/56.
血壓持續上升 高壓84，低壓56，穩定下來了
This is Kitami. The mother's condition is stable.
我是喜多見，母親的情況穩定了
The smoke is getting thicker, evacuate immediately.
煙越來越濃了，馬上撤離
We can't move Kurumi until we stop the bleeding.
幫胡桃止血之前不能移動
This will be a bit cold.
會有點涼喔
Where are you right now, Dr. Hina?
比奈醫師，你現在在哪？
I've joined TO1.
我在一號手術室
Okay.
好的
Kurumi has bleeding in the pericardium.
胡桃的心包內有出血
I will have to open her chest here.
必須在這裡開胸才行
I need the wire twister. And portable oxygen.
我需要鋼線持針器，還有隨身氧氣瓶
Can we have them drop supplies from the bridge ahead towards the ship?
能不能從前面的橋 投放醫療物資到船上？
We will catch it.
我們來接應
Komaba here, setting Toyomi Ohashi Bridge as the handover point.
我是駒場，將投放點設在豐海大橋
Sharing the location.
分享位置資訊
We'll be okay here, so please go, Dr. Hina.
這裡沒問題了，比奈醫師，你過去吧
Yes.
是
We've got the emergency TO3 ready for transport.
三號緊急車輛已經到了，我送你去
Then I'll go!
不如我送吧
I'm good with motorcycles.
我騎摩托車技術不錯
Please.
麻煩你了
The boat passed Kachidoki Bridge, emitting white smoke.
屋形船通過勝鬨橋了，有白煙冒出
Thank you.
謝謝你
This is Tsurumaki. I've reached the bridge.
我是弦卷，我到橋上了
Got it. Just stay and--
好的，在那裡等…
Drop the tools to the emergency team.
給接應人員投放物資
What's happening?
怎麼回事？
She's seizing.
她發生痙攣
Ms. Maki. I'll have a look at your chest.
真紀小姐，我檢查一下胸部喔
What's happening?
怎麼了？
Ms. Maki is cyanotic from cardiogenic shock.
真紀小姐心因性休克導致發紺
This will be bright.
會有點刺眼喔
Monitor shows AV block.
心電圖顯示房室傳導阻滯
Ms. Maki, keep fighting!
真紀小姐，要撐住喔
Kurumi! Kurumi…
胡桃…
What's happening to Kurumi?
胡桃怎麼了？
Cardiac arrest. Mr. Senju, please start CPR.
心臟停止，千住隊長，做心肺復甦
Kurumi. Kurumi, come back.
胡桃…回來吧
Kurumi, hang in there!
胡桃，加油啊
Ms. Maki, Kurumi is fighting too.
真紀小姐，胡桃也在努力喔
-Kurumi, can you hear me? -Check the monitor.
-胡桃，聽得到我說話嗎？ -檢查心電圖
How is she?
怎麼樣？
She's not coming back.
不行，沒有恢復
Dr. Tsurumaki, over here!
弦卷醫師，這邊
Throw it!
丟過來吧
Kurumi!
胡桃
Mr. Senju, I'm giving adrenaline.
千住隊長，我來注射腎上腺素
Ms. Maki, you'll be getting some medicine now.
真紀小姐，我幫你投藥喔
Come back together with Kurumi.
跟胡桃一起回來吧
Come back now.
撐住啊
-Ms. Maki! -You'll be okay.
-真紀小姐 -沒事的
Kurumi, can you hear me?
胡桃，聽得到我說話嗎？
Just a little more… hang in there.
再堅持一下，加油啊
Keep fighting, Ms. Maki!
加油，真紀小姐
Kurumi!
胡桃
Dr. Hina!
比奈醫師
What happened?!
發生什麼事了？
Ms. Tsurumaki jumped off the bridge onto the boat…
弦卷醫師從橋上跳到船上了
Is she okay?
人沒事吧？
Kurumi, it's almost over, hang in there.
胡桃，快好了，再堅持一下
You can do it.
加油
Chief Kitami!
喜多見主任
Dr. Hina.
比奈醫師
Chief Kitami, Mr. Senju. Oxygen.
喜多見主任、千住隊長，氧氣
Thank you.
謝謝
Breathe in.
快吸氧
Are you okay?
你還好吧？
Yes.
我沒事
-I'll take care of Kurumi. -Dr. Hina, wear the life jacket.
-胡桃交給我 -比奈醫師，穿救生衣
-Mr. Minato, Mr. Kosuge, ambu. -Yes.
-湊先生、小菅先生，甦醒球 -是
I'll perform open-chest direct hemostasis and CPR.
我要開胸止血和做心肺復甦
Let's focus on the patient in front of us. Cooper.
專注於眼前的病患，組織剪刀
I'll open the sternum in one go.
我要一口氣打開胸骨
Mr. Senju, please hold her down.
千住隊長，請壓住她的身體
This might hurt a bit.
會有點痛喔
-Inserted. -Removing the wire.
-注射了 -取出鋼線
Here, oxygen.
吸氧
Wire removed.
鋼線取出來了
She's bleeding from the artificial vessel.
人工血管正在出血
I'll apply pressure and start CPR.
我來加壓，做心肺復甦
Come on, Kurumi. Hang in there.
加油，胡桃，加油
Okay. Ambu, please.
好，給我甦醒球
Ms. Maki.
真紀小姐
Fight, Kurumi. Come on.
加油，胡桃，加油
Block is gone. Blood pressure stable.
阻滯沒了，血壓穩定
Her pulse is back. What does the monitor say?
心臟恢復跳動，心電圖怎麼樣？
Blood pressure is back too.
血壓也恢復了
You did so well, Kurumi.
你很棒呢，胡桃
You did great.
你做得很好
Mr. Senju.
千住隊長
We can move them now.
可以運送出去了
Prepare for evacuation, ready the backboard.
準備撤離，備好長背板
-Roger! -Please take the monitor.
-收到 -心電圖交給你們了
This is Kitami. Kurumi needs emergency surgery
我是喜多見，胡桃需要進行緊急手術
for bleeding from the right ventricular pulmonary artery duct.
處理右心室肺動脈導管出血
I want to minimize transport time,
為了盡量縮短運送時間
so TO1 needs to be on standby at the riverbank.
一號緊急車輛到河岸待命
This is TO1, transport of the captain is complete, we can move.
這裡是一號緊急車輛 船長已送醫，隨時可以移動
Komaba here, the rendezvous point will be at Sea Forest Waterway.
我是駒場 會合地點定在海之森水上競技場
Transfer the patient to the rescue boat off Odaiba and then to TO1.
將患者運送到台場的救生艇上 再送到一號緊急車輛
Copy that.
收到
Governor, please request cooperation from the Coast Guard.
赤塚知事，請向海上保安廳請求協助
There is a risk that the houseboat might explode.
屋形船有爆炸的危險
Tell them to temporarily close the area near Odaiba.
請要求他們暫時封鎖台場附近的海域
They should already be on their way.
他們應該快到了
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Secure an evacuation route.
去確認撤離路徑
Yes, sir.
收到
-Mr. Senju, guys, have oxygen. -I'll help.
-千住隊長，你們也吸點氧氣 -我來幫忙
Forget about us, just focus on the patients.
不用管我們 你們優先考慮患者就對了
Please.
麻煩了
Dr. Hina, keep applying pressure to the bleeding.
比奈醫師，繼續加壓止血
Make sure the tracheal tube doesn't move during transport.
運送途中請注意不要讓氣管插管脫落
Yes. Hang in there, just a little longer.
好的，再一下就好，要撐住喔
There's a risk of explosion.
有爆炸的危險
Rescue boats towing, ensure a safe distance from the houseboat.
拖曳的救生艇 務必跟屋形船保持安全距離
Harumi, copy that.
晴海號收到
This is the Coast Guard patrol boat Yamabuki.
這裡是海上保安廳的巡視船山吹號
Maritime closure complete near Odaiba. No ships in the vicinity.
台場附近的海域 已經封鎖完成，周圍沒有船隻
MER has arrived!
行動急診室抵達
-The dock is this way. -Yes.
-碼頭在這邊 -好的
The consecutive surgeries cause a risk of droplet transmission.
連續動手術會有接觸飛沫傳染的風險
-Please ensure thorough disinfection. -Yes.
-要徹底擦拭消毒 -好的
Dr. Aoto.
青戶醫師
I'll handle the disinfection.
消毒工作交給我吧
That is about all I can do.
我能做的就是這些了
Thank you, Dr. Aoto.
麻煩你了，青戶醫師
I'll take care of all the dirty work. Please prepare for the next surgery.
髒活都讓我來做 你們去準備下一場手術吧
Dr. Otowa, please rest in preparation for the surgery.
音羽醫師 你先休息一下，準備應付手術
Slowly, watch your step!
小心腳下
Dr. Fuyuki, prep for massive transfusion under general anesthesia.
冬木醫師 準備施行全身麻醉和大量輸血
-Got it. -Secure the patients!
-收到 -固定好傷患
Retreat at full speed.
全速撤離
Kitami!
喜多見
Senju, respond!
千住，快回答
This is Senju.
我是千住
Everyone is safe.
大家都沒事
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Keep giving her pure oxygen and set IV drip to 200 per hour.
繼續提供純氧 點滴流速每小時200，麻煩了
-Let's go. -Yes.
-走吧 -是
You got her!
交給你們了
Mr. Senju!
千住隊長
Are you okay? I'll bring oxygen.
還好嗎？我去拿氧氣
I'm fine, just go!
我沒事，去吧
This is Kitami. We'll be there soon.
我是喜多見，馬上到達
TO1 open.
一號手術室，開門
-I will be waiting in the anteroom. -Thank you.
-我在前室待命 -辛苦了
I will perform a right ventricular pulmonary artery duct repair.
現在開始進行 右心室肺動脈導管修復手術
This pediatric heart re-surgery
這種兒童心臟二次手術
requires dissection of adhesions near the coronary arteries.
需要剝離冠狀動脈周邊纖細的沾黏
It's our hardest operation thus far.
是我們至今為止難度最高的手術
I know everyone is tired from the consecutive surgeries,
我知道大家連續動手術很累
but let's stay focused and give it our all.
但是要集中精神，全力以赴
Yes.
-是
Dr. Hina is more familiar with the patient.
比奈醫師比我更熟悉患者的情況
I will assist.
我來當助手
Usually, a full cardiopulmonary bypass is required for this complex suturing.
通常這種手術有需要用上 心肺體外循環的複雜的縫合部分
Dr. Hina, does your arm allow you to do this?
比奈醫師，你手臂的傷可以應付嗎？
I can do it.
可以
-Setting up the ECMO. -I'll take over.
-接上葉克膜 -我來接手
-Dr. Fuyuki, how are her pupils? -Reflecting light.
-冬木醫師，瞳孔如何？ -對光有反射
Good. We can't return blood with ECMO, so we'll minimize blood loss.
好，葉克膜不能回輸失血 務必盡量減少出血量
-Electric scalpel. -Electric scalpel set to 20.
-電刀 -電刀設定在20
DeBakey forceps.
-德貝基組織鉗
Another DeBakey here.
-我也要德貝基組織鉗 -好的
ECMO established.
葉克膜設好了
-Start it up. -Yes.
-開始回流吧 -是
Dr. Otowa, apply pressure and suction to the bleeding area.
音羽醫師 出血部位的加壓和抽吸就麻煩你了
Yes.
好的
Adhesions removed. Let's start by clamping the pulmonary artery side.
剝離完成，先從肺動脈開始止血
Right angle forceps.
直角鉗
Vascular tape, red.
-血管止血帶 -紅色的
Blood pressure, 85/60.
高壓85，低壓60
Bleeding 250.
出血量250
-Satinsky. -Here.
-薩丁斯基鉗 -是
Clamped. Is the full flow achieved?
-阻斷血管了 -流量開最大了嗎？
Yes, running at 3000 RPM, 2.5 liters.
是的，轉速3000，2.5公升
-Then, let's proceed to the heart. -Yes.
-好，接下來到心臟了 -好的
Be aware that Kurumi has an abnormal coronary artery course.
胡桃的冠狀動脈走向異常 要多加小心
-Okay. Electric scalpel. -Electric scalpel.
-好的，電刀 -電刀
Blood pressure dropping to 45/21.
血壓下降，高壓45，低壓21
Suture between right ventricle and conduit is torn, bleeding. 5-0 Prolene.
右心室和導管之間的縫合處裂開 出血中，5-0縫合線
-Tokumaru, how's the flow? -Flow is only at 50%.
-德丸，流量如何？ -只剩五成
What about using a balloon catheter for hemostasis?
用氣球導管止血怎麼樣？
-Let's do it. Dr. Otowa. -I'll assist.
-就這麼辦，音羽醫師 -我來協助
A 10 Fr, please.
3.33公釐的導管
Ms. Natsume, 5-0 with both ends ready.
夏梅小姐，5-0縫合線，兩端接好
10 Fr balloon catheter.
3.33公釐的氣球導管
Dr. Hina, syringe.
比奈醫師，注射器
Inserting the balloon.
要置入氣球了
-It's in. -Inflating with 5cc.
-放進去了 -注射5毫升
Stitching with purse string, 5-0 Prolene.
荷包縫合，5-0縫合線
5-0.
5-0
-Please drop the needle. -Cooper.
-請放下針頭 -組織剪刀
-Draining the water. -Please do.
-要瀝乾水分 -麻煩了
-Removing the balloon on three. -Understood.
-數到三移除氣球 -好的
One, two…
一、二
-Three. -Clamping.
-三 -夾住了
-Removed. -Bleeding has stopped.
-氣球已移除 -出血停止了
Resuming dissection by the heart.
繼續心臟部分的剝離
Electric scalpel.
電刀
Right angle forceps.
直角鉗
-Vascular tape. -Yes.
-血管止血帶 -是
-I'll pull it once you receive it.
-你接過去後我就拉了
Secured. Satinsky clamp, please.
按壓住，給我薩丁斯基鉗
Suturing laceration on the artificial vessel. 5-0 Prolene.
接下來縫合 人工血管的裂口，5-0縫合線
5-0.
5-0
Removing from the pulmonary artery side.
從肺動脈側鬆開
Please do.
麻煩了
-Removed. -Removing from the heart side.
-鬆開了 -從心臟側鬆開
-Please. -Removed. How is it?
-麻煩了 -鬆開了，情況如何？
No bleeding. Suture hemostasis is successful.
沒有出血，縫合止血成功了
Rescue and transport of the injured are all completed.
所有傷患都已獲得救助並送醫
Thirty-four minor injuries.
本次出動，輕傷34人
Six serious.
重傷6人
And casualties…
死亡人數…
Zero!
零
Good work.
辛苦了
Well done.
太好了
Are you leaving, Minister Kamata?
蒲田大臣，您要回去了嗎？
Yes, I have an important meeting.
對，我有個重要的會議
Thanks to Dr. Aoto's efforts,
多虧有青戶醫師的積極表現
we were able to conclude with no fatalities.
這次出動才能以零死亡人數結束
Thank you for introducing him to us, Minister Kamata.
真是非常感謝蒲田大臣您的引薦
I'm glad I could help.
能幫上忙就好
Please continue to support my direct jurisdiction over Tokyo MER.
今後也請您多關照 直屬於都知事的東京行動急診室
Certainly!
好
Yes!
太好了
Thank you for your hard work. Please pass my regards to Senju's squad.
辛苦了，也請替我問候千住隊長他們
-Good work! -Oh, same to you.
-辛苦了
Please have these.
那個，不嫌棄的話請用
Oh, thank you!
好耶，謝啦
Thanks.
謝謝
I'll take this one.
那我要這個
Good work.
辛苦了
You all are incredible.
你們都很了不起
All of you are fully committed to saving lives.
為了拯救所有人的性命 拼盡了自己的全力
It's truly incredible.
真的太厲害了
Especially Dr. Tsurumaki.
尤其是弦卷醫師
I'm sorry for treating you like an intern.
我還把你當住院醫生看待，很抱歉
No, I'm not that significant.
沒關係，我也還有很多不足
I'm sure if Dr. Otowa had done the surgery,
剛才的手術如果由音羽醫師來做
the adhesion separation would have been done much quicker.
應該能更快地完成剝離沾黏
You're right.
也對
And Dr. Otowa would also have done the suture hemostasis more smoothly.
音羽醫師在縫合止血方面也會更順利
But, you know,
不過嘛
Dr. Hina, you don't have to take on everything alone.
比奈醫師，你不必獨自背負一切
Dr. Otowa was doing the compression hemostasis.
音羽醫師負責加壓止血
Dr. Fuyuki was managing the overall condition.
冬木醫師負責管理整體狀況
Ms. Natsume was handling the instruments,
夏梅小姐負責遞器械
Ms. Minh was replenishing the materials,
敏小姐負責補充物資
and Tokumaru was managing the ECMO.
德丸負責操作葉克膜
That's why Kurumi's surgery was a success.
所以胡桃的手術才那麼成功
And that's not all.
不僅如此
Senju's men and the firefighters,
還有千住隊長的小隊和消防廳
the rescue squad, the Coast Guard and the police,
救難隊、海上保安廳、警方
and Mr. Komaba and Governor Akatsuka at the government.
都廳的各位 以及駒場先生和赤塚知事
We couldn't have saved everyone without them.
沒有他們的話 我們是無法拯救所有人的
We need more than doctors.
這不只是醫生的功勞
That's how, with everyone's help,
我們一直以來都像這樣
we have been saving lives all this time.
借助大家的力量去拯救生命
That's the kind of team MER is.
行動急診室就是這樣的團隊
Well then, everyone, thank you for your hard work today.
好了，大家今天都辛苦了
Thank you.
-辛苦了
And then Dr. Hina jumped off the bridge!
然後呢，比奈醫師從橋上跳下去了
Wow, that's amazing.
哇，好厲害喔
Hey, now. Kurumi, let's not talk about that anymore.
好啦，胡桃，別再說那件事了
Dr. Hina is Kurumi's hero after all.
比奈醫師是胡桃的英雄嘛
-Yeah! -No, it wasn't anything special.
-沒錯 -沒有啦，沒那麼誇張
It was so cool.
真的超酷的
I didn't expect you to have that in you.
沒想到你還留了這一手
MINISTER KAMATA RESIGNS, EFFECTIVELY OUSTED
（蒲田大臣辭職 實際上是被撤職？）
UNDER INVESTIGATION FOR UNDERREPORTING INCOME
（過少申報政治獻金，接受搜查中）
It was the talk of the Ministry. That the dud was hiding his fangs.
在厚勞省內也引起了討論 說廢物露出了隱藏已久的獠牙
That money-grubbing Minister turned out to have lots of dirt.
那個貪財大臣 做了不少見不得人的事呢
But the MER project shouldn't be affected.
但行動急診室的計畫應該沒有受影響
Spread this organization nationwide.
將這個組織推廣到全國吧
What will you do now?
接下來有什麼打算？
I'll go back to my hometown and start over as a resident.
我會回老家，從住院醫生重新做起
I've always been half-hearted in everything I've done,
一直以來，我做事總是半途而廢
but I've realized I want to continue being a doctor.
但我還是想當一名醫生
Next time we meet at a site, I'll be a doctor you can rely on.
下次在現場見面時 我會是一個可靠的醫生
Dr. Otowa is leaving,
音羽醫師要離隊了
and it seems the newly arrived Dr. Aoto is leaving as well.
新來的青戶醫師好像也要離開了
What will you do about a new second doctor?
副手醫師一職要怎麼辦呢？
You've already decided on a candidate, right?
你應該已經定好人選了吧？
I'm sorry, but not yet.
抱歉，還沒
Um.
請問
Would anyone want to take on the role of MER's second doctor?
這裡有人願意 當行動急診室的副手醫師嗎？
It seems best to consider transferring to another hospital.
果然還是轉到別的醫院更為妥當
No, wait… Huh?
不…咦？
What's the matter, Dr. Tsurumaki?
怎麼了，弦卷醫師？
Could I…
請問…
be given the opportunity to be Tokyo MER's second doctor?
能讓我擔任 東京行動急診室的副手醫師嗎？
Weren't you going to Cardiac Surgery?
你不是要去心臟血管外科嗎？
Dr. Kitami.
喜多見醫師
What do you think?
你怎麼想？
Is Dr. Tsurumaki up to the task of being MER's second doctor?
弦卷醫師能擔任 行動急診室的副手醫師嗎？
Isn't it more about what Dr. Tsurumaki herself thinks?
比起我的想法 弦卷醫師的想法更重要，不是嗎？
Right now,
現在的我
there's no way I can replace Dr. Otowa.
肯定不能取代音羽醫師
However,
但是
MER is made up of reliable staff.
行動急診室有一組可靠的隊員
If I keep working with that team,
只要我繼續跟這個團隊一起工作
someday, surely,
總有一天
I'll be able to catch up to Dr. Otowa.
我一定可以追上音羽醫師
I'll become a doctor who surpasses Dr. Otowa.
我一定可以超越音羽醫師
It won't be that easy for a newly trained doctor.
剛研修結束的新人醫生 就別沾沾自喜了
She only just recovered from an injury.
明明才剛受了傷
She's a woman, and it's dangerous.
而且還是女生，很危險的
Her gender and her career shouldn't matter, should they?
性別和職業無關，不是嗎？
I respect Dr. Tsurumaki
身為一名醫生
and trust her
我很尊敬弦卷醫師
as a physician.
也很信任她
But she just finished her residency.
但她才剛研修結束啊
Over the past year, Dr. Tsurumaki has gained experience in the MER field.
過去這一年裡，弦卷醫師 已經累積了行動急診室現場的經驗
She knows MER better than anyone here.
她比在座的各位都更了解行動急診室
There's no one better suited
沒有人比弦卷醫師
to replace Dr. Otowa than Dr. Tsurumaki.
更適合接替音羽醫師的職務
Dr. Takanawa, you mentored her. What do you think?
高輪醫師 作為弦卷醫師的指導醫師，你說呢？
Unfortunately…
雖然很遺憾
if Dr. Tsurumaki has made this decision…
但如果弦卷醫師已經下定決心…
then I will support her.
那我會支持她
Use the knowledge you gained with me
請將從我這裡學到的知識
to excel in emergency medicine.
用在急救上吧
Thank you very much.
非常謝謝您
Dr. Tsurumaki.
弦卷醫師
I look forward to working with you.
今後也請多指教了
Yes.
是
Dr. Hina has become the second doctor.
比奈醫師成為副手醫師了
I see.
是嗎？
I can't count how many times you've saved us.
我都數不清被你救過多少次了
There's gas on the ground. Stand up and breathe.
氣體都積在地面，站起來呼吸
If I let you die, it'll affect my assessment.
我可不想因為對你見死不救 影響到自己的考績
Dr. Otowa.
音羽醫師
You're a doctor, after all.
因為你是醫生
Nothing is more important than saving a life.
世界上沒有比生命更重要的事物
Don't give up.
別放棄
Live.
給我活下來
Pulse is back!
心跳恢復了
Chief Kitami!
喜多見主任
Damn you!
開什麼玩笑
You dragged us into this.
擅自把大家拉進來
And that's it for you?
結果就這樣結束了？
Come back, damn it!
給我回來
Don't do any medical practices that have a risk of death, ever again.
請你不要再做出 會危及性命的醫療行為了
Right.
好
Because I had you, I could get away with being reckless.
因為有你在，所以我才可以亂來
You were solid.
你很堅強
The best partner.
是我最好的夥伴
I only did what was expected of me as a doctor.
我只不過是做了一名醫生該做的事
I never condoned your dangerous methods.
我從來都不認可 你不顧危險的醫療行為
The MER we're spreading nationwide
之後擴展到全國的行動急診室
will prioritize safety.
會是重視安全的組織
If you spread MER, even more lives can be saved than before.
你來推廣行動急診室的話 就能拯救更多的生命
Let's work together as colleagues.
作為志同道合的夥伴，一起加油吧
The new MER
新的行動急診室
might not become an ally, but a rival to Tokyo's branch.
可能不是你們的夥伴，而是競爭對手
I believe that
我認為…
Dr. Hina should be the second doctor.
比奈醫師能勝任副手醫師一職
I'll leave Tokyo MER in your hands from now on.
今後東京行動急診室就交給你了
So this is the ultimate ER car that you were aiming to get.
這就是你追求的急診車的最終形態啊
25% increase in operating room volume,
手術室體積增加了25%
newly equipped with X-ray fluoroscopy and DSA,
配備了新的X光透視 以及數碼減影血管造影
and allows for catheter treatments that were impossible until now.
之前無法進行的導管治療 也可以操作了
The question is, who will master it?
問題是誰能將它運用自如呢？
I heard she just arrived in Japan.
我聽說她剛到日本了
Yokohama's chief doctor.
橫濱的主任醫師
You can't overlook it either.
真不能小看你啊
It's the talk of the town.
傳得沸沸揚揚了呢
You two were involved in the past, right?
說你們倆以前有過一段情啊？
Chief Kamoi is an excellent doctor.
鴨居主任是一名優秀的醫生